Guide to the Yale Objects Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Yale objects collection, 1697-2002; Series I
  - #202 Pair of baseball gloves, leather, open tops and made without fingers, bearing name of owner C.P. Williams (Y. 1882s) (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - #203 Zinc case (rusted) in which was found Ezra Stiles' honorary degree from Princeton, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - #204 Zinc case (rusted). Held diplomas of Ezra Stiles, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - #205 Yale banners of the Class of 1891. Blue linen and white lettering (in 4 pieces) (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - #206 Brown crockery mug with 3 handles, inscribed with signatures of members of class of 1902, celebrating triumphant football season in Fall, 1901 (Box 43)
  - #207 Silver goblet. "Presented to Oliver Phelps VI by the Class of 1881, Sheffield Scientific School.. ." Lettering and decorative motifs made at Tiffany & Co, 1884 (Box 43)
  - #208 Metal engraving plate of Yale seal that was in common use circa 1896-1925. Probably used for a letterhead (in a brown case) (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - #209 Miniature Wooden oar, with blue paint and lettering saying YALE ELM, undated (Box 43)
  - #210 Black academic hoods (4) of Stephen V. Benet. Yale, Middlebury, Dickinson, and Rochester, 1932-1940 (Box 44)
  - #211 Wooden look cover for Yale Class Album of 1874. Drawing on covers (Box 45)
  - #212 Wooden plaque with Yale seal in brass contains motto "Lux et Veritas", undated (Box 45)
  - #213 Wooden and brass plaque; presenting the Stephen Wise Award to Yale University from the American Jewish Confress for its publication of Judaica, 1955 (Box 45)
  - #214 Fraternity Insignia, emblem of He Boule--Owl painted on black velvet, with wooden frame, undated (Box 45)
  - #215 Embroidery sampler worked by Kezia Stiles of her Family Register. Framed, 1772 (Box 46)
  - #216 Plaster face cast of John Brocklesby, taken when he was age 21, a sophomore at Yale, 1832 (Box 47)
  - #217 Silver embossed matchbox "exchange favor" at Sophomore "German" dance, 1895 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - #218 Deck of playing cards with Yale Seal, 1896 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - #219 Wooden Fraternity Paddle of Delta Kappa Epsilon with drawing etched in it, 1909 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - #220 Wedding fan of Elizabeth Stiles, wife of Ezra Stiles. Ivory and Papers, oriental scene, mainly gray, 1757 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - #221 Velveteen runner with Yale seal pennant and bulldog; green, red, and gold. Put out by Fatima cigarette company, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - #222 Sterling silver and ivory trowel, used at the laying of the cornerstone of Sterling Memorial Quadrangle. Engraved, 1917 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - #223 Sterling Silver Cup--prize for Intercollegiate Glee Club contest. Metropolitan District, 1932 (Box 48)
  - #224 Check for $100 from the U.S. Government to C.S. Thompson to symbolically cover the expense of the first Yale Flying Squadron. Framed, 1918 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - #225 Various metal drawing instruments of Francis Loomis, in a case, lined with brown velvet, undated (Box 48)
  - #226 1894 decennial reunion jacket; white duckcloth with blue trim (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - #227 Columbia University academic hood, undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - #228 Lantern carried at the Yale Bicentennial, 1901 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - #229 Yale band costume: white pants, white jacket, blue jacket, and mortarboard cap, undated (Box 49)
  - #230 Two broken clay pipes, 1880's (Box 50)
  - #231 Clay pipe used at Class Day, 1889 (Box 50)
  - #232 Fragment of a clay pipe, 1871 (Box 50)
  - #233 Unidentified collection of 19 clay pipes, undated (Box 50)
  - #234 Pouches of class day (1919, 1924S) tobacco (Box 50)
  - #235 Bottle of tobacco used by class, 1865 July (Box 50)
  - #236 Collection of Class Day tobacco pouches, 1919-1940 (Box 50)
  - #237 Silver Loving Cup with the shape of a football supported by 3 football players; inscribed "to Walter Camp of Yale from graduates of the University", undated (Box 50A)
  - #238 Unidentified trophy; plastic and metal, 1957-1963
  - #239 Lamp made and used by William Jones Weeks (Y. 1844). Wood and metal, 1840s
  - #240 Wood model of St. Thomas More, Park St, New Haven, undated
  - #241 Silver loving cup for Harvard-Yale Regatta, 1894 June 28 (Box 51)
  - #242 The Freshman; plaster model of a bulldog head for the Memorial Quadrangle, undated (Box 51)
  - #243 Plaster bust of James Donnelly, campus policeman of the early 20th century. Designed by R.Y.M. Hitchcock, 1912 (Box 51)
  - #244 Horn (may have been used at the Bicentennial); metal with blue and white ribbon, undated (Box 51)
  - #245 Alpha Delta Phi paddle key "To Paul Moore from C.G.Curtiss" key, undated (Box 51)
  - #246 Carved wooden spoon; metal plate with unknown insignia; metal plate inscribed: "Presented to H. Augustus Cleveland by the class of 1870" (Box 393)
  - #247 Carved wooden spoon; metal plate with unknown insignia; metal plate inscribed: "D.L. Huntington. Presented by the class of 1855 Yale College June '54", 1854 (Box 226)
  - #248 Carved wooden spoon; metal plate with unknown insignia; metal plate inscribed: "Fortiter Fedeliter Feliciter. Brinley D. Sleight. Presented by the class of '58.. .", 1857
  - #249 Carved wooden spoon with the initials "P.C.S.", 1871 (Box 226)
  - #250 Carved wooden spoon with initials "N.P.H.", 1867 (Box 392)
  - #251 Carved wooden spoon; metal plate with unknown insignia; metal plate inscribed: "Presented to George Todford by the class of 1865... " In wooden case, 1864 (Box 225)
  - #252 Carved wood spoon; metal plate inscribed "Presented to Robert K. Weeks, by the class of 1862... ", 1861 (Box 224)
  - #253 Wood walking stick with sterling silver tip and head. Inscribed "St. Anthony German 1908" (Box 226)
  - #254 Wood walking stick belonging to a student, 1870's (Box 226)
  - #255 Elaborately carved bamboo walking stick presented to Noah Porter by Joseph Neesima, undated (Box 308)
  - #256 Wood cane with metal band inscribed "C.B. Tinker, Yale University", undated (Box 226)
  - #257 Wooden cane for Alumni reunion with program scroll in cane, 1939 (Box 308)
  - #258 Wood cane belonging to the Rev. Thomas Buckingham, one of the founders of Yale College, circa 1646-1709 (Box 227)
  - #259 Wood cane with gold band inscribed "Russel H. Chittenden from the Yale Class of 1901 SSS At their Vicennial Reunion", 1921 June 21 (Box 226)
  - #260 Wood cane for 1899 reunion with program scroll in cane, 1939 (Box 227)
  - #261 Axe which served as the mace for the Miniature Treegrowers Association, undated (Box 395)
  - #262 Wooden bat - reads George N. Miles, 1889 (Box 391)
  - #263 Wooden bat, undated (Box 391)
  - #264 Piece of mantel from the first Yale library, undated
  - #265 Yale banner, Class of 1855 (Box 228)
  - #266 Metal key, inscribed: "Key to the Porter Gateway. Presented to Miss Jennings by the Yale Corporation." In a case, undated (Box 52)
  - #267 Engraving plate for cut of the Yale bowl; copper and wood, undated (Box 52)
  - #268 Winner's pennant for Yale Fall Regatta, October 1883, in a frame (Box 52A)
  - #269 Framed Masonic apron of Rev. Samuel Wales (Y. 1767), tutor at Yale 1769-1770, Livingston Professor of Divinity 1782-1793, undated (Box 52A)
  - #270 Dies for striking Yale Bi-Centennial Medal. Designed by Bela L. Pratt, 1901 (Box 53)
  - #271 Penniman Memorial Library of Education plaque; copper and wood, undated (Box 54)
  - #272 Ellsworth Huntington Library Plaque; wood, undated (Box 54)
  - #273 Wood fraternity paddle with names, 1897-1902 (Box 54)
  - #274 Yale Fraternity paddle; wood with greek letters and "November, 1901. Arthur Norris Collins, 1903. Percy Hall Jennings 1904", 1901-1904 (Box 54)
  - #275 Drawing of an unknown insignia in a frame, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - #276 Wooden spoon of Charles H. Owen (Y. 1860), one of the Spoon Committee, 1859 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - #277 Wooden spoon with Yale design drawing, circa 1871 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - #278 Pigskin Yale postcard, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - #279 Silver hat buckle, engraved "Yale 1848" (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - #280 Watch fob in the delta shape of the scholastic society insignia; gold; inscribed with letters Chi Delta Theta, 1824, verso: John C. Beach (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - #281 Bronze watch fob showing a "Y" and "92" in the center; and "Vincensimus Quintus" "Yale" in the border; with white-bordered blue ribbon, 1892 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - #282 Piece of wood from a limb of the large Elm tree that stood on the site of the former Osborn Hall on the Old Yale campus, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - #283 Scroll of congratulations to Yale University on the occasion of its 200th anniversary from the Imperial University, Tokyo, Japan (in a black laquer box), 1901 (Box 56)
  - #284 Three-handled Yale University Club Cup, copper and silver, inscribed with members' names, 1902 (Box 57)
  - #285 Three-handled silver loving cup; with raised lettering: "Presented to Dean Henry P. Wright... ", 1908 (Box 57A)
  - #286 Pewter stein inscribed: "Yale University Tennis Association, 1902... " (Box 57)
  - #287 Silver Loving Cup, inscribed: "Delta Kappa Epsilon Association of New York to Henry Parks Wright Dec. 15, 1910" (Box 58)
  - #288 Mory's Cup for Conspicuous service to Yale, presented to Clarence W. Mendell, 1931; silver (Box 59)
  - #289 Silver loving cup of W.F. Foster (Y. 1894, Law) from the Book and Gavel Society, 1903; later belonging to Charles P. Sherman; ivory handles (Box 59)
  - #290 Three-handled pewter loving cup, inscribed "The Thirst Club October 1906" (Box 59)
  - #291 Pewter stein inscribed "Yale Record Baseball 1905... " (Box 60)
  - #292 Pewter stein inscribed "Charles Stetson, Psi Upsilon Beta 1900" (Box 60)
  - #293 Pewter stein inscribed with name of John Stafford Hunter and Alpha Delta Phi, undated (Box 60)
  - #294 Pewter stein inscribed "P.K.C. Dec. 10 1902 F.S." (Box 60)
  - #295 Pewter stein trophy for Yale Spring Games, 1895 (Box 60)
  - #296 Wood walking stick with silver tip and head, with initials "W.J.B." on top and "A.S.H." and "E.W.G." on sides, undated (Box 308)
  - #297 1902 class pipe in 4 sections; in suitcase
  - #298 Ceramic stein (mended) from a Yale fraternity. Names of members are inscribed on the mug, 1903 (Box 62)
  - #299 Wooden test tube rack used by Benjamin Silliman, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - #300 Chinese abacus used by Theodore Dwight Jr. (1796-1866). On the verso is written: "Theodore Dwight Jr, Chinese Abacus used for counting in every... ", circa 1800s (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - #301 Three-handled loving cup (handles are modeled on antlers) presented to "Professor D. Cady Eaton from his class in the History of Art, 1906-1907" (Box 62)
  - #302 The Algernan Sydney Sullivan Award; awarded to Anson Phelps Stokes, circa 1925-1927 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - #303 Collapsible telescope, glass and leather; trademark J.B.L.; property of Elias Loomis, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - #304 Complicat annuli or Puzzling Rings that belonged to Elias Loomis--made of ivory, circa 1811-1889 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - #305 Ruler and slide ruler belonging to Elias Loomis, circa 1811-1889 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - #306 Gold seal ring of Jedidiah Morse, undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - #307 Leather wallet belonging to Benjamin Silliman Sr, circa 1779-1864 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - #308 Watch presented by the Class of 1757 to their tutor J.A. Hillhouse (Y. 1749), circa 1756 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - #309 Three cameo studs belonging to Elias Loomis, circa 1811-1889 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - #310 [Gold]? pencil. "Class of 1848 to Prof. E. Loomis, N.Y." (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - #311 Copper engraving plate with the arms and motto of the Woolsey family and the name Theodore S. Woolsey engraved at the base, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - #312 Instruments used by Elias Loomis. Identifiable are two pencils, pen knife, magnifying glass, transparencies, needle-pointed dividers and 6 other tools, circa 1811-1889 (Box 63)
  - #313 2 Metal engraving plates used in the making of the book on Loomis family geneology, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - #314 Carved paddle that reads "Thomas Beer '11 from E.S. Blair, C.W. Davis and J.R. Kilpatrick.", 1909 (Box 64)
  - #315 Painted enamel tray from President Hadley's home, undated (Box 64)
  - #316 Three-handled silver loving cup with pine border; inscribed "Whitehead C. Duyckinck. A testimonial from his classmates.. .", 1905 (Box 65)
  - #317 Scroll of congratualtions from the Yale Association, Tokyo Japan on the 77th anniversary of the birth of Simeon E. Baldwin (Y. 1861), 1919 (Box 220)
  - #318 Christmas greeting to George Parmly Day from Charles E.L. Thomas in Japanese, circa 1930 (Box 221)
  - #319 Masonic apron worn by Roger Sherman, circa 1776 (Box 66)
  - #320 Three-handled ceramic loving cup belonging to Frank R. Kimbley Incised with names, 1897 (Box 67)
  - #321 Clay drinking mug with various figures and objects of college life inscribed on it. Bottom of mug: "January 5, 1894 F.P.F." (Box 67)
  - #322 University Patrol hat, circa 1920s (Box 67)
  - #323 Blue felt banner with white lettering: Yale 1909s (Box 68)
  - #324 Sword presented to Lt. Mather A. Abbott (1919h) U.S.N.R.F, by the men of the Yale Naval Training Unity Fleet, with scabbard and leather case, 1918 (Box 318)
  - #325 Sword and scabbard presented to Matthew M. Miller by the class of 1864, 1861 (Box 316)
  - #326 Sword and scabbard belonging to Midshipman Julian Bishop, U.S.N, circa 1923 (Box 315)
  - #327 Black wooden stick with Yale in gold letters at one end. At the other end is a label "From the estate of Hon. Simeon E. Baldwin Y.C. 1861 Gift of his children 1928", circa 1861-1923 (Box 226)
  - #328 Black wooden cane with ivory knob (cracked) with letters "G & S"; metal ring under knob reads "Yale"; smaller ring reads "F. Bacon 1838 L.F.F.", circa 1838 (Box 308)
  - #329 Gold watch--one side has the initials HB, the reverse side reads, "Presented to Rev. Hiram Bingham by friends on his completing the translation.. .", 1890
    See archivist
  - #330 Watch. On face is printed "Alderne, London" On stem is stamped number 1335. Winding key is engraved with number 8, undated
  - #331 Gold watch, no identifying markings, undated
  - #332 Yale Glee Club letters used on face in place of numerals. Engraving inside back case: "To Barty [Marshall Bartholomew] with gratitude from the Yale Glee.. .", 1928
  - #333 Hand seal press for Yale College, class of 1859, undated (Box 69)
  - #334 Hand seal press for Yale College, class of 1860, 1906 (Box 69)
  - #335 Hand seal press which is a "replica of 1906 seal made for G.P. Day" (description on original tag), nundated (Box 69)
  - #336 Hand seal press [appears to be a Yale University seal], undated (Box 69)
  - #337 Hand seal press -- origninal tag read: "Third seal sent from Y. Press to Mr. Lohmann, presented to Lib. Jan. 1939" (Box 69)
  - #338 Hand seal press for the seal of Yale College, circa early 1900s (Box 70)
  - #339 Hand seal press for Sloan Physical Laboratory, undated (Box 70)
  - #340 Hand seal press for Yerkes Laboratory for Primate Biology, Orange Park, Florida, undated (Box 70)
  - #341 Hand seal press of the Yale seal made for the Treasurer's office, 1906 (Box 70)
  - #342 Chester Plimpton Memorial medals: on one side is the profile relief of Chester Plimpton. Other side shows two depictions of two Greeks, undated (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - #343 Door knocker, oversized replica of a Yale key, undated (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - #344 Door latch and other original hardware from the doors of the Rev. Samuel Russell's house in Branford, circa 1742 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - #345 The doorknocker from the home of Daniel Cady Eaton, Yale 1860. The knocker is an oversized key and is now mounted on a wooden plaque, undated (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - #346 Die for the Francis Bergen Medal, undated (Box 72)
  - #347 Silver plate awarded for the Peter Wallace short story contest, undated (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - #348 Yale Banner: blue felt with white felt lettering, undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - #349 Pen and ink rendition of the Yale seal--framed--signed in the lower right hand corner "Tiffany.. ." [rest illegible], undated (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - #350 Bicentennial medals (5). Copper? medallion with the words "Yale University Bi-centennial 1701-1901" attached to blue ribbon, 1902 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - #350.1 Four bricks: (1) North Sheffield Hall, (2) South Middle, (3) Yale building, (4) North Middle, circa 1770 (Box 73)
  - #351 Bronze medals (28), many of them are in cases wrapped in papers and sealed with the Tiffany & Co. wax seal, 1901 (Box 74)
  - #352 Buttons (approx. 50) showing the face of Kingman Brewster, circa 1964-1976 (Box 75)
  - #353 Die for the Campbell medal for highest standing in Medical Studies, undated (Box 76)
  - #354 Plated brass key to the State Capitol to "Charles G. Morris, 1928 From Jos. Hollander BPT. [Bridgeport], CT" (Box 77)
  - #355 Bronze plaque of the Yale seal, undated (Box 77)
  - #356 William Lyde DeVane medal--Phi Beta Kappa Award. Shows profile relief of [DeVane?] in academic garb, undated (Box 77)
  - #357 Cement or plaster profile bust of Edward C. Herrick, Treasurer of Yale, 1852-1862. Bust is set in a blue velvet oval frame, undated (Box 78)
  - #358 Roger Sherman coat of arms: pen and ink rendition--framed--with the description: "He beareth Or, a lion, rampant... ", undated (Box 79)
  - #359 Blazer insignias for Berkeley, Calhoun, Pierson, Saybrook, Jonathan Edwards, Trumbull, and Davenport Colleges, undated (Box 80, Folder 1-8)
  - #360 Artist's rendition of the coat of arms of Morse College, undated (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - #361 Artists designs for college china, undated (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - #362 Record [about Yale Anniversary], 1849 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - #363 Wooden panel with a painted depiction of Alumnae Hall. Bottom reads "Alumnae Hall Yale College... " Artwork signed Wilson H. Barrett B.F.A. 1925, undated
  - #364 Large red and white flag commemorating the Class of 1910's participation in World War I, post 1918 (Box 82)
  - #365 Large tapestry framed--unidentified but possibly a fraternity insignia, undated
  - #366 Ivory-carved elephants in procession--line of elephants is attached to a wooden tree limb-like base, undated (Box 219)
  - #367 Brown snakeskin pocketbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #368 Ivory beads and bracelet, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #369 "DeForest Prize Medal for Excellence in English Composition and Speaking Awarded to Henry Root Stern, 1903" (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #371 Framed poem from "John Brown's Body," by Stephen Vincent Benet about Georgia, 1980 (Box 218)
  - #372 Etchings of Abraham Lincoln and Benjamin Franklin [issued exclusively to members of the Bibliographile Society], undated (Box 83)
  - #373 Album of Edith Wharton commemorative stamps (first issue in New Haven), 1980 (Box 84)
  - #374 Certificate of membership in the admiral clubs, American Airlines, for A.B. Giamatti, 1978 (Box 84)
  - #375 Two books: "Il Teatrino nella villa reale di Monza," and "La Leggenda di Teodolina negli affreschi degli zavattari testo di liana castelfranchi vegas.", 1975 and undated (Box 84)
  - #376 Replica of the "Corona Ferrea--Duomo di Monza" mounted on a marble base, undated (Box 85)
  - #377 Chinese pottery bowl in a gift box, undated (Box 85)
  - #378 Ceramic three-handled stein from Zeta Psi, Class of 1897 with names (Box 86)
  - #379 Ceramic three-handled stein with raised markings around it, undated (Box 86)
  - #380 Ceramic three-handled stein -- around the sides are the Yale Seal and various inscriptions, 1899 (Box 86)
  - #381 Class or fraternity stein--on one side is a diamond within which are two hands shaking--stein is covered with names, undated (Box 87)
  - #382 Beer mug made by Robert K. Root (Y. 1897). Among the markings on the mug are: Yale seal, various Latin and Greek inscriptions, "Here's to good old... " (Box 87)
  - #383 Class of 1897 stein--raised knoblike protrusion reads 9Y7. Names of the class members are inscribed on the rest of the stein (Box 87)
  - #384 Silver loving cup which reads: "To Professor George Jarvis Brush, M.A, L.L.D, with the esteem and affection of the graduates of 'Sheff,'... ", 1901 (Box 88)
  - #385 Silver trophy on black base. Inscription reads "Big Three Little Three Debating Tournament Held at Amherst 1940 Winner Yale McGeorge Bundy and... " (Box 89)
  - #386 Silver award presented to Henry P. Wright by the professors of Yale College in honor of his 25th Anniversary as Dean of Yale College, 1909 (Box 90)
  - #387 Silver tray inscribed:"John Q. Lockman From Yale '98 Gratefully and Affectionately 1898-1948." There is also an etching of Old Brick Row (Box 90)
  - #388 Tray inscribed: "On the occasion of the 250th Anniversary of Yale a piece of silver of the year 1701 and this of 1951 were presented by Yale in Britain.. " (Box 90)
  - #389 [Silver-plated]? candelabra. Down the sides of the column base it reads "To John Christopher Schwab MCMII Universitas.. .", 1902 (Box 233)
  - #390 Chinese scroll, undated (Box 91)
  - #391 Frame made from pieces of the Yale fence, undated (Box 92)
  - #392 Brass tube for a deed. Inscription reads "Deed/Frank Bergen to Yale University/May 19, 1919/To found a Memorial of/Francis Bergen/Class of 1914
  - #393 Four Yale flags: blue background with white Y in center, undated (Box 314)
  - #394 Ceramic jug used by the students to fetch water. Beige with blue flowers, circa 1850 (Box 93)
  - #395 Bronze diamond-shaped Delta Kappa Epsilon plaque, circa 1956 (Box 94)
  - #396 Large blue and gold banner, class of 1890
  - #397 Replica of Michelangelo's "David.", undated (Box 95)
  - #398 Statue of Botticelli's "The Birth of Venus.", undated (Box 95)
  - #399 Black nameplate given to Henry Chauncy Jr. by Dr. Kwon oh-Byung, Congressman, Republic of Korea, January 1972 (Box 95)
  - #400 Hand stamp with insignia used as a letter seal by E. Loomis. Wooden handle brass seal, 1841 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - #401 Blue ribbons with 1902 stamped on them (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - #402 Key to the side entrance of South Sheffield Hall (adjacent to Prospect St.) which leads to the clock tower (observatory), circa 1919 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - #403 Bronze Yale Bicentennial medal. [This medal was flown aboard the first operational space shuttle "Columbia" STS-5], 1901 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - #404 Stamp with Carl Lohmann's signature, circa 1927-1953 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - #405 Nails from Old Connecticut Hall, 1750-1753 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - #406 Tuning fork used by Alexander U. McAlister (Y. 1866s), leader of the Glee Club, circa 1866 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - #407 Fifty year reunion ribbon for 1883 Sheffield, 1933 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - #408 Copper plate for Robert Nelson Corwin's book plate, undated (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - #409 Glass plate negative of the following receipt: "Received New Haven, January 5th 1833 of Mr. Wm. Lyon. Forty dollars... toward a fund of 100,000 dollars... ", undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - #410 Profile bust mounted on wood with the following inscription plaque: "Presented to Gov. Simeon E. Baldwin by Re. J.J. Downey, Pastor of St. Michael's... ", 1912 (Box 180)
  - #411 Plaque for Alpha Delta Phi, 1832? (Box 97)
  - #412 Silk red, white, and blue rope used to form the aisle for the Presidential party at the William H. Taft Inaugural Ball. Members of the Floor Committee held the rope, 1908 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - #413 Flag carried to salute the Presidential party during the Taft inaugural march by Mrs. C.J. James, wife of a member of the Floor Committee, 1908 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - #414 Atmos pipe nail used to push down tobacco in a pipe, undated (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - #415 Badge shaped like a policeman's badge which reads: "Whiskey Inspectory 99." Possibly a gift to Jim Donnelly [Yale Police] from the Class of 1902, circa 1902 (Box 98, Folder 2)